JACOB LEROY GARLICK

6121 Ammons Street, Arvada, CO 80004 | 970-749-0868 jacobgarlick@msn.com

References are available upon request

Personal Website: https://jakeg-9191.github.io/Bootstrap-Portfolio/

GitHub: https://github.com/JakeG-9191



HIGHLIGHTS

PERSONAL TRAITS

- Project Management Experience
- Willingness to Learn and Educate
- Great Communication Skills
- Individual and Team Player

Friendly, professional, punctual and self-motivated with excellent technical, written and oral skill sets to compliment experience. Able to adapt to new settings and work environments in timely manner. Driven by understanding of personal responsibilities and how those affect the prime organization and key stakeholders at large. Always striving to improve education, communication and intersectionality between various disciplines to address complex issues. Productive in both team and individual environments, able to generate results with little direction and extremely driven with a proven track record.

TECHNOLOGY COMPETENCIES

Software

Highly proficient with Microsoft Office and its components; Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Project, etc. as well as Slack. Experience with CRM software including Salesforce and Accela. Experience with Project Management software such as Trello and Prolog. Competent with command line, Git Bash and Visual Studio Code.

Languages, Frameworks, Libraries and Other Experience with HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.JS, JSON, AJAX, PHP, Laravel, Express and React. Previous experience with Git, GitHub and Heroku for personal and team projects and deployment. Prior work with API integration and familiarity with Postman and other API services.

Databases

Experience with MongoDB, MySQL, and Firebase data persistence.

EDUCATION

Spring 2020 Master of Arts – Political Science, University of Colorado – Denver [Denver, CO]

Fall 2019 Professional Certificate – Web Development, University of Denver [Denver, CO]

Spring 2014 Bachelor of Arts – Political Science, Fort Lewis College [Durango, CO]

Minor - History, Fort Lewis College [Durango, CO]

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

October 2018 - Energy Efficiency Coordinator, Department of Public Health and Environment | City & County of Denver [Denver, CO]

Present

• Helped continue to develop and promote Energize Denver Benchmarking Program, including working on the development of major overhaul of process for overall program effectiveness

- · Assisted in policy and resource development for Green Building Ordinance, assisted in public outreach and education campaign
- · Supported Climate Action Team on new initiatives, programmatic and technological research and policy development to address major climate change issues

November 2017 – July 2018

Interim Department Director, Department of Tribal Planning | Southern Ute Indian Tribe [Ignacio, CO]

- Returned to Planning Department upon Tribal Council request, solidified process for federal grant drawdowns to expedite closeout of previously constructed projects
- Developed partnership with State of Colorado (CDOT and CPW), and La Plata County to address deficient safety concerns, culminating in agreement for major construction project to mitigate animal-vehicle collisions
- · Worked with Bureau of Indian Affairs and newly staffed Tribal Grants Division to further streamline reporting and compliance for federal grants, resulting in substantial savings in time and costs for planning and construction of projects

September 2017 – November 2017

Project Manager, Department of Construction & Project Management | Southern Ute Indian Tribe [Ignacio, CO]

- · Assumed additional authority over Tribal construction projects, including individual phases of the housing development and other road projects
- · Continued to improve occupation specific skills focused on elements of engineering, design and construction with large scale projects including residential, commercial and infrastructure work

August 2016 – September 2017

Apprentice Project Manager, Department of Construction & Project Management | Southern Ute Indian Tribe [Ignacio, CO]

- · Moved into pre-design, engineering and construction phase roles for major construction projects
- Trained extensively and rapidly in construction management tools, created new workflow to better support review period for internal and external partners
- · Worked closely with several Tribal departments to pursue the first major housing development in decades, producing dozens of new housing units and preparing several acres of land for future development

April 2016 – August 2016

Interim Department Director, Department of Tribal Planning | Southern Ute Indian Tribe [Ignacio, CO]

- · Assumed control of and created new workflow for P.L. 93-638 federal contracts with the Bureau of Indian Affairs that cut review time for entities from several week to within two
- Created a detailed schedule of major planning documents and their required iteration updates, beginning with a backlogged document that defines all land use planning and had not been updated since 2005
- Finalized two major transportation planning related documents that provided ability to solicit annual federal, state and local grant funding for future projects

MY HOBBIES

In my free time I enjoy as much time outdoors as possible, constantly looking for the next opportunity to take my Tributary HD raft out for some white-water adventure. I also enjoy camping, snowboarding, ultimate and frisbee golfing, traveling, mountain biking and some quality time in the gym, leisurely reading, attending live music and engaging in outdoor and adventure photography.